# GIANG NGUYEN

(+44) 7904035063  $\diamond$ ntg2208@gmail.com  $\diamond$  Linkedin Newcastle upon Tyne, UK

#### **OBJECTIVE**

MsC in Data Science and 2 years of experience AI Engineer, seeking a challenging position applying Analytical Thinking and Machine Learning. A wide range of experience working on Computer Vision, Deep Learning and analytical & predictive projects - now ready to apply to solve real-life problems.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Northumbria University, UK

Expected in May 2023

MsC Data Science

- Expected First Class Honours
- Postgraduate Global Scholarship.

# Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, Vietnam

May 2020

Bachelor of Engineering Advanced Program in Electrical and Telecommunication

- Equivalent Upper Second Class Honours.
- Publication: Deep Learning Based Approach Implemented to Image Super-Resolution.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

**Programing Languages** Python, R, SQL, C++.

Libraries/Tool Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Keras, Tensorflow, Pytorch, ggplot2,

Excel, Tableau, Google Sheet, git

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Seedcom Joint Stock Company

Nov. 2020 - Dec. 2021

Research and Development AI Engineer

Vietnam

- · New Retails Data Platform
- Customized queries to match business specification, performing analysis in real time, detecting trend, segmenting customers, segmenting product, ad optimization.
- · Fashion improvement recommendation systems
- Used Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) to build a fashion items object detection and localization to identify what users are wearing with an accuracy of 92%.
- Built fashion items recommendation and outfit recommendation systems to improve customer's shopping experiences and targeting to increase customer click-rate, cross-sell and total selling revenue.
- Deployed model in form of Application programming interface (API) for store and web access.

# **Vulcan Labs Company Limited**

Jul. 2020 - Nov. 2020

AI Engineer

Vietnam

- · Improve Styling Camera Application
  - Deployed Deep Learning and Computer Vision Solution to cloud-based application and IOS's API.
- Researched Topics: Generative Adversarial Networks, Salient Object Detection, Image Segmentation
- Researched models: StyleGAN, StyleGAN2, U-Squared-Net, Deeplabv3Plus.

## Emage Development Pte. Ltd.

Jul. 2019 - Jul. 2020

AI Engineer

Vietnam

# · Defective semiconductor detection using Machine Learning

- Used Image Processing for features extraction and Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) to build a Defective semiconductor Detector with an accuracy of 98%.
- Deployed Machine Learning model on factory's computer with inspection time of 0.2 sec/image.
- Build a Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) application for semiconductor image annotation for train and evaluate Machine Learning model.

#### Robert Bosch Engineering And Business Solutions.

May. 2019 - Nov. 2019

Embedded Software Engineer - Internship

Vietnam

# · Renault & Nissan Interior Application for Electrical Vechicle

- Trained with multiple problems in C/C++: Parallel Programming, Application's Design Pattern.
- Developed application used for debugging Application's User Interface.

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### **Customer Churn Prediction**

2022

- Built and compare: Support Vector Machine (SVM), XGBoost, Random Forest, Decision Tree.
- Got the prediction accuracy of 99%.

# Natural Language Processing with Disaster Tweets

2021

- Cleaning raw Twitter's data, preprocessing and fed into LSTM for text classification.
- Bagging models: BERT, ROBERTA, XLNET for a better prediction
- Got the prediction accuracy of 80%.

## **Customer Sentiment Analysis**

2019

- Built Human's Emotion Classifier: Angry, Disgust, Fear, Happy, Sad, Surprise, Neutral.
- Applied Face Detection and Emotion Recognition to evaluate customer satisfaction.
- Deployed into a cloud-based systems for Point-of-Sale (POS) system access.

# **Student Attendance Monitor**

2019

- Applied Face Detection and Face Recognition for Student Attendant monitoring for undergraduate.
- Combined multiple Convolutional Neural Network end-to-end Recognition systems.
- Applied Optical Character Recognition (OCR) to Verify Student with Information on card.

#### TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

Google Ask Questions to Make Data-Driven Decisions	July 2022 Coursera
HSE University Probability Theory, Statistics and Exploratory Data Analysis	August 2020 Coursera
HSE University Discrete Math and Analyzing Social Graphs	August 2020 Coursera
University of California, Davis SQL for Data Science	August 2020 Coursera
DeepLearning.AI DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer	July 2020 Coursera
DeepLearning.AI Deep Learning	June 2020 Coursera